A Guide to the George Parsons Lathrop Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7075-a
George Parsons Lathrop [1851-1898] Collection 1872-1896
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7075-a
9 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [1963 Dec 17] 1965 Feb 25
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - Quotation beginning "Social convention.. .", 1882 Jan 27; AMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - George Parsons Lathrop to Mary Louise Booth, 1872 Sep 16; ALS, 1 p.
    [Sends "something in a similar vein to that from wh(ich) I drew 'Washington's Watch'"; says he and [Julian or Nathaniel] Hawthorne once considered writing a series of children's tales; says he periodically feels like writing some of the plots he thought of and would be glad to place them in
    Harper's Bazar
    if she likes them; mentions possible trip to New York and bringing his wife Rose Hawthorne Lathrop to see her.]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to Herbert Stanley Renton, 1881 Apr 7; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Regrets not being able to lecture before Renton's union; says he may be able to next winter if he doesn't got to Europe. ]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to unknown, 1887 Oct 31; ALS, 1 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of the addressee's letters about Charles Follen McKim and William Rutherford Mead for the Cyclopeadia; says the matter is settled; says he would have been glad to assist, as he knows both men and could have spoken or written to them.]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to Mr. Freiberger, 1889 Feb 11; ALS, 1 p.
    [Asks him to send a copy of the paper which contained the letters for the Hebrew Charity Fair. ]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to Mr. Johnson, 1890 Nov 6; ALS, 2 p.
    [Answers some questions from Johnson's India correspondent; says he doesn't know of an allusion to "parchment pennies" in Nathaniel Hawthorne's works; suggests that the correspondent remembers "Pine-Tree Shillings" from
    Grandfather's Chair
    alludes to
    Le Sage's Dialogues, Serious and Comic, between Two Chimneys of Madrid
    , which is sometimes in the same volume as
    Devil on Two Sticks
    gives a brief synopsis of the latter; mentions Asmodeus, a character in
    . ]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to James Jeffrey Roche, 1891 Sep 19; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions just returning from New York; regrets not being able to participate in the Authors' Reading for John Boyle O'Reilly's monument fund, as he'll be in New York at the time Roche wants him in Malden, Massachusetts; says he may be able to help in some other way.]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to Houghton, Mifflin & Co., 1894 Nov 2; ALS, 1 p.
    [Encloses an addition to the Appendix (probably to
    A Story of Courage
    ); asks that the following line also be added to the Contents, under appendix: IV. Rev. James Curley, S. J.]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to [Samuel Sydney] McClure, 1896 May 25; ALS, 1 p.
    [Asks to meet with McClure or the editor of the magazine (
    McClure's Magazine
    ?) the next day.]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to Mr. Wilson, [ca. 1878] Sat p.m.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Says he returned the proof of [James] Bayard Taylor's poem, probably "A Lover's Tests," with annotations by Thomas Bailry Aldrich, to Thomas Niles; asks Wilson to take the enclosed note to Niles and to "ask him if, in the N[o] N[ame] Vol[ume] of poems,
    A Masque of Poets
    , he wishes poems run on to each other, instead of breaking pages"; says it would look better if they weren't run on.]
  - George Parsons Lathrop to Carey, Wed 1:30 p.m.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Says that he fears she may not have received the note he sent to her at
    Century Magazine
    , perhaps because it was forwarded to New London; asks if Walter [Learned?] is in town and where he will be staying.]